into the meeting itself. So recording is
started. We are letting folks in the
meeting. Uh good afternoon everybody. Uh
please uh welcome this afternoon. We are
admitting people into the meeting. We'll
give it just a minute to make sure that
we have everybody in the lobby that's
switched over. Sometimes that can take a
minute or two. Um, and just uh to uh as
an introduction, my name is Dominic
Erllo and I'm the director for the
Center for Medical Cannabis and
Psilocybin here at New Mexico Department
of Health. Um, and Chris Pesusky is the
chair of this committee. And just a
couple of reminders, please remember
that we do record these. So, uh, by
joining in, you have agreed to being
recorded. We do need to get individuals
full legal names. Uh as far as for
comments um and we do include that
within um our minutes
and in addition to that just please
remember because we are recording it.
Please be careful about language because
this is open we post these on the
website and so they are open to anyone
of all ages. So we just have to be
careful. If there are names of
particular species, products or anything
like that that do contain profanity,
please just use the initials for the
individual item and otherwise just uh be
just a little careful and cautious. Uh
for those who have asked about why we
don't uh have uh everybody's face on and
just have the few people from the
department and the board who have
cameras available. There are two reasons
for that. One is because uh with the
number of people that we have joining,
if people are in areas where they do not
have very good internet connectivity, it
actually increases the likelihood that
they get dropped from the call and have
to rejoin. Um and since that does happen
sometimes regardless, we want to try to
minimize that as much as we possibly can
so people can participate. And the other
is because occasionally there are things
in background behind people that again
are not appropriate to be seen on the
video. And so we want to ensure that uh
we are able to include the video in full
on the website. So with that in mind, I
will turn it on over to Chris. Uh Chris,
thank you very much and the meeting is
yours.
>> Thank you Dominic and thank you all for
being here. as is ritual. Now in this
space, I'm going to start the meeting
off with just uh 30 seconds of silence
to in an attempt to create a small
container of compassion in a world full
of chaos. Um so if you'll just drop in
with me for just half a minute.
Oh, that was abrupt today. All right,
welcome everybody to the what is this?
Our fourth meeting now for the
propagation committee. Um, so glad to
see familiar names in the chat and
excited to get started today. We're just
going to continue where we
But first we need to start with
introductions. Remember, if you um do
not introduce yourself, you are not
eligible to vote. So, please uh make
your presence known. Let us hear your
voice uh throughout this entire process.
And also, when it come time to voting,
um please abstain from voting if you're
from out of state. Um, okay. With that
said, please uh introduce yourselves,
tell us who you are, where you're from,
and if you have any affiliations with
any anybody that has a stake in the
game.
>> And if you'd like to introduce yourself,
please just raise your hand on the
computer. It's you utilize the hand icon
near the top of the team's window. Uh,
if you're on a phone, it click on the
three dots, the ellipses in the menu,
and then the hand icon will appear. And
then if you're joining through voice
only on the phone, press star five to
raise and lower your hand.
>> Fantastic. First we have Don Moser.
I have allowed your mic. Please unmute
and begin when ready.
>> Yes. Thank you so much. Uh my name is
Don Moser. I live in Las Vegas, New
Mexico.
And uh having moved here four years ago
after an advertising career in Houston
and I'm just very very I'm a beginner. I
don't I know very little about this
although I'm absolutely convinced that
psilocybin
is healthy. So I will be basically
auditing just listening because this is
all new to me. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much for that. Next we
have Hannah Rose.
Hannah, I've um allowed your mic. Please
begin when ready.
>> Thank you. My name is Hana Rose. I'm
here in Silver City, New Mexico. And um
I'm really excited to get involved with
this program. My intentions are to be a
practitioner and a grower. Um, I'm in
school for my bachelor's in social work
and I would love to bridge social work
and medical psilocybin.
>> Thank you very much, Anna. Next, we have
John Esleck. John, I have allowed your
mic. Please begin when ready.
>> Hello, my name is John Esleck. Um, or
Jonathan Esleck. Uh, I'm a home
micologist. Uh, I've done some work with
NM Fungi and uh, Four Corners Fungi. I'm
just here to assist as best I can.
>> Thank you very much for that. Next, we
have Estan. Estavan, I have enabled your
mic. Please begin when ready.
Seem to have a few issues there. Uh
if you want to check if your microphone
is working, I'll give you a few more
seconds and if not uh just uh lower your
hand and what we'll do is we'll continue
going onwards. But uh if we can maybe uh
figure that out uh maybe join in via uh
telephone um I believe the number is on
uh is the number provided Dominic? Just
a quick question.
>> Uh it is in the invitation. Yes,
>> in the invitation. All right. So the
number will be there and uh just
remember to unmute yourself. It's just
uh star six, but just uh let me know if
you're having any other issues. In the
meantime, Frraasier, Matteo, Matteo,
Frraasier, pardon me, I don't know which
way around. Uh I've enabled your mic.
Please begin when ready.
Sorry, I took a moment there. Um hi, I'm
Matteo Frasier. I'm a uh a filmmaker and
also a licensed um a vertically
integrated cannabis cultivator in the
state of New Mexico. Um been studying
the psychedelic space for a long time.
Um and just here to collaborate and
network and learn um about what we're
doing in the city of New Mexico.
>> Thank you very much for that. Next we
have Asher Singer. Asher, I've enabled
your mic. Please begin when ready.
>> Hi. Yes. Uh Usher Singer here. I um I'm
based out of a Chimaya, New Mexico. And
uh I run a uh a smallcale uh fruit and
vegetable farm. We also do um commercial
uh mushroom production. And um yeah, I'm
just curious to learn uh you know, more
about this program and um yeah, see if
there's anything I can do to help or be
involved in some way.
>> Thank you very much for that. Next, we
have James Brown.
James, I've enabled your mic. Please
begin when ready.
>> Afternoon everyone and Chris, thank you
again for chairing this. My name is
James Brown. I'm a doctor of pharmacy
here from New Mexico. I'm out of
Albuquerque. I'm a veteran, so I'm
representing that community. I'm also a
facil facilitator trained in PAT, uh,
that's psilocybin assisted therapy out
of Oregon. Um, and so I'd be
representing that space as a facilitator
and practitioner. There's also one of
the groups that's just new forming is a
group called
Five Degrees North Healing Foundation,
which is a nonprofit that will be
focused on having a center to provide
services for veterans, first responders,
focused on trauma.
Uh, thank you again for allowing me in
this space today.
>> Thank you very much for that. Next, we
have Zoe Spiraltos.
Zoe, I have enabled your mic. Please
begin when ready,
perhaps a few technical issues today.
Um, if you're experiencing any technical
difficulties, uh, that's not a problem.
if you just uh lower your hand and uh
what we'll do is we'll continue on. Um
if you manage to fix it or um if if
that's not successful, there is a
telephone number on the screen uh that's
kindly been provided by both Jorge and
as Dominic. Uh you can call in that way
and to unmute yourself, it's simply star
6. Um so yeah, next we have Estan. Hello
again. Um mic has been enabled, so
please begin when ready.
>> Uh good afternoon everyone. Uh, my name
is Stevon Hernandez, lifelong New Mexico
resident, owner of New Mexico Fungi, and
president of the New Mexico Micology
Guild. Um, I will be here in a little
bit of a limited capacity till about 4
PM, at which point I will be, you know,
fully into this meeting. So, thank you.
>> Thank you very much for that. Next, we
have MO Frasier. Um, I have enabled your
mic. Please begin when ready.
>> Hi there. I'm Mao Frasier. I'm a
filmmaker and owner of a production
company here in northern New Mexico. I'm
from Northern New Mexico. I have a
special interest in micology and
psilocybin research. So, I'm just here
to learn more about what's happening
here in the state.
>> Thank you very much for sharing. Next,
we have Gregory Evans. Gregory, I have
enabled your mic. Please begin when
ready.
Greetings and thank you again for
continuing this process, Chris, and your
focus and alignment. Um, I feel like we
could have used a couple minutes of
reflections
this week. Um, but yeah, thank you. Uh,
my name is Gregory.
>> I can start getting
>> Okay.
>> My name is Gregory Evans. I'm an
independent researcher and home
micologist with no affiliation. I'm a
Santa Fe resident. My intention is to
support the development of the program
through committee recommendation process
that is aligned with emerging research
and best practices.
>> Thank you very much for sharing. Um we
have a hand up there. I believe it might
be Zoe. We'll find out. Um in any case,
I have enabled your mic to unmute. Press
star six.
Hello everyone. I apologize for the um
my computer never unmuted
and um I'm so sorry I can hear myself so
I'm trying to lower the volume here.
Okay. Um my name is Zoe Baraltos. I'm
here from Buffalo, New York. Um and I'm
here really just to kind of listen and
learn. I'm a psychiatric nurse
practitioner and a clinical assess
assistant professor at UB School of
Nursing. And this has um been an area of
interest of mine for research and also
my intention is to bring it into
practice as well. So I'm very excited to
be here and I thank you all for allowing
me to be here.
>> Thank you. We appreciate that. Um so
next we have James B. James I have
enabled your mic. Please begin when
ready.
>> Hey this is uh James Blackboard. Um, and
I I have uh some experience in micology
enough to to fall in love with it and
mushrooms in general. They're
fascinating, amazing things. Um but
mainly I wanted to say that I have
personally experienced family members
who have struggled with anxiety and
depression and other uh mental kind of
issues who had been medicated uh for
most of their adult life who after
turning to uh psilocybin treatment um a
complete 180 better than any other
man-made drugs before. So, I'm very
excited to see where this goes and um
yeah, I just love to be a part of this
and I thank everybody for all their hard
work and um input on this. This is
wonderful.
>> Thank you very much for that. And just
to highlight some comments in the chat,
uh Eric Barlow uh states, "I'm Eric
Barlow. I live in Las Cruus. No
affiliations." Ben Edwards states, "Hi
everybody. I'm Ben Edwards. I live in
New Mexico for 50 years. I'm a soil
micologist working on land restoration
and reforestation professionally. I'm
also an amateur micologist and have
engaged in indigenous ceremonies for
over 30 years. Thank you for that. Uh
next we have Don Moser. Don Mosa, Las
Vegas, New Mexico novice. And finally,
John Esleck. I believe I forgot to
mention that I'm located in Albuquerque.
So, thank you very much for your
comments, everybody. And I turn it back
to yourselves.
Either Chris or Dominic, please go
ahead.
Did we get Dan?
>> Oh, I don't believe we did actually.
Correction. My apologies for that. So,
Dan, my apologies. Go, go right ahead.
I've enabled your mic. I really
apologize for that. Dan Hust.
>> Hello, Daniel Houston. Uh, Rose City
Laboratories, Portland, Oregon. I've
been testing psilocybin for the legal
industry for the last three years or so
and testing prior to that. Uh, just here
to let you guys know our experiences and
and uh trials and tribulations out here.
Um, I love it and congratulations. Thank
you.
>> Thank you very much for that. Um, and
finally, we got one more comment in the
chat by James B. Also forgot to mention
I'm out of Clovis, New Mexico. So, that
is everyone. Back to you, Chris.
>> Brilliant. Thank you all for introducing
yourselves and bringing your your voice
and yourselves to this meeting.
I appreciate so much all of this input
and uh you know especially some of you
joining from out of state and Oregon
coming to share lessons learned um
super shout out to you all um because
this program is going to impact us in
New Mexico but you you all are bringing
outside uh knowledge and sharing it and
that's awesome. So, we're going to
continue on the propagation outline
we've been working over on for the last
couple weeks. We're going to kind of
switch it up a little bit and start with
batch definition. Um, and then we'll go
into the sunset clause language um
around four when Estabbon can kind of
engage fully because he was awesome
enough to provide that language for us.
So, um if somebody can pull up the
propagation
should be able to see it should be able
to see it at this point.
>> I cannot Can anybody else see it?
>> Can if other people can see it, can you
do a thumbs up emoji? Okay, we have a
lot of people who can't. Okay,
>> since this must be a technical glitch on
my end,
>> let me stop sharing and try again just
in case.
Bear with us please everyone.
>> Okay, can you see it now Chris?
I cannot.
So Chris um at the top um in the menu uh
do you see something that says view?
>> Yes.
>> Um try different arrangements within
there.
Let's
just do
>> well here. Let me let me also do this.
Is there anyone else using a thumbs up
emoji at the moment who cannot see uh
the document?
>> Should I leave and come back?
>> Uh why don't you go ahead, Chris? We'll
we can wait for a moment. While you do
that, actually I'll do introductions of
our team. We uh we skipped over that. So
yeah, we'll see you in a moment. So uh
good afternoon everybody. As I mentioned
in the very beginning of uh the um of
the meeting, my name is Dominic Erllo
and I'm director for the New Mexico
Department of Health Center for Medical
Cannabis and Psilocybin. Um Jorge, would
you go ahead and introduce yourself?
>> Sure. Well, hello everyone. Thank you
for being here and thank you for taking
the time. My name is Jorge Gonzalez. Um
I am the program manager for the medical
psilocybin program
>> and Adrian.
>> Hi good afternoon everyone. My name is
Adrian Estrada. I am a health educator
here with the program and excited to see
how everything is evolving.
>> And Ishmael.
>> Hello everybody. My name is Ismael Zut.
I'm one of the health educators too um
and part of the health education team.
Really excited to be here. So thank you.
and uh Robert.
Oh, I can hear he's actually uh with
somebody else at the moment. Uh we also
have Dr. Robert Truckner who is our
medical director for the center and for
the program. So, and Chris, good timing.
Are you able to see the document now?
Oh, and you're on mute, Chris.
>> I can't, which is so interesting because
I was able to see the PowerPoint. So,
>> yeah, that's very
>> Okay. Well, let's work around it. And uh
I think we can communicate by um
if if you can help me kind of guide the
>> outline.
>> I'll put the sections into uh the chat
as well like we did last time. So you'll
have them there in the chat and as well
as everyone else. Okay. So uh I think we
were talking about batches was going to
be the first part. I'll put the whole
thing on in. Uh it includes some
information from Colorado which is just
there for for anformational
uh point. Um and uh so what we currently
just have here and again this is just as
a placeholder is a batch defined as a
single harvest lot processed under
uniform conditions. No regulated size
requirement. And again the the comment
here is what would be standard language
to define this regarding harvesting and
size of the lot.
So uh suggest
>> you put it in the did you put it in the
chat?
>> I'm just doing it right now.
>> Okay.
>> Takes me just a moment to uh to do both.
>> No,
thank you. I just uh when I re-entered
there was nothing in there. I'm like is
that not working too? So
>> no no it just yeah often times sometimes
it just shows from when you enter. Um so
anybody who has suggestions uh go ahead
raise your hand or comments regarding
it. So, and before we get into comments,
I just want to say I put Colorado's
um testing
p or recommendations down below here at
the bottom. And so, I I feel like it's a
good starting point, but if people have
a, you know, a different starting point
they want to offer, I'm welcome to that.
And um yeah, let's go ahead and and
start taking comments now.
Okay, first we have James B. James, your
mic is enabled, so please uh begin when
ready.
>> Thank you. Um yeah, I know there's a lot
more scientific minds who who could give
a little bit more of an opinion on this,
but um in in section two there where a
bat shall be considered um all the
mushrooms containing from a single
inoculation in a flush where a new flush
um would be considered a new harvest
because the inoculation contains, you
know, you're introducing um the same
material in the substrate that you get
from the first flush as you may get from
a second or third flush. essentially
it's all the same um kind of thing. So,
I would vote to take out uh the language
of flushes and just leave it for an
inoculation and a substrate and
mushrooms harvested from that specific
substrate would be considered a flush
just cuz there's really not going to be
any differences um I want to say
biologically, but I know that's probably
not the right word between the first,
second, and third flush cuz it's all
from the original um inoculation. So, I
I think that would be better for, you
know, cost for growers and and testing
and everything else. Um, and and there I
I can't really see any negative reasons
for doing it that way. I don't think the
variance uh would really be anything
noticeable or really make a difference.
>> And James, just as a question, so I did
that as a a revision at the moment and
put that in the chat. Does that sound
reasonable? Am I capturing what you're
suggesting?
>> Um,
yes. Yeah, from the same substrate. Uh,
because there's only, you know,
definitely one flush, uh, maybe two
flushes, especially commercially and for
the purposes. I can't see too much being
harvested, three more flushes beyond,
um, just because of the potential of a
lot of different things. So, yeah. Um,
yeah, that that looks great.
>> Great. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Next we have Dan Houston.
Dan, your mic is enabled. Please begin
when ready.
>> Um, all right. So,
um, personally, I think that, uh, you
guys can actually eliminate, uh, most
all of this when you're trying to define
a batch. Um, batches if because you guys
are going down the homogeneous route and
everything has to be homogenized.
um that that pretty much it doesn't at
that point doesn't really concern
whether it's the first flush, second
flush or what. Um there should if you
guys want to put some regulation in
there. Maybe uh you know some a batches
uh what's harvested within a 7day or 10
day period period kind of stop it at
that. um and then uh you know and set a
weight limit for a batch. Um and only
I'm only saying this because it's
homogenized product. So it has to be
homogenized. And when you test
homogenized product, you're taking a
primary sample and a and a uh duplicate
sample to make sure that the product is
is homogeneous. So, if we're verifying
it's homogeneous, do we need do you need
all of this
in here?
Thank you, Dan. That's a good good
question. And uh I think some of these
uh were actually added prior to the
discussion about homogenization.
So what I did do is I took that first
bullet and just said potency testing
should be conducted uh for all batches
of psilocybin which have been
homogenized using best practices for the
testing of psilocybin and psilosin which
we actually have the other analyt uh
that we had mentioned earlier will fix
that language. So you're thinking that
with that we take the what is currently
points one through four just delete
those and put in potentially a time
limit. So like I I think you had said
seven days. Am I correct on that?
>> Yeah. And I I don't do a lot of I don't
really do a lot of growing. I just know
a lot of growers. But basically um you
guys can talk about Yes. what's harvest
if if you want to put stuff in there.
what's harvested within a certain time
frame and you know one batch is
a a kilogram or 2 kilogram or whatever
you guys want to determine one batch
size is. So a batch size is good and but
I mean it yeah I don't think you need to
worry about whether it's first flush,
second flush. I mean what if they're
growing and they can harvest everything
on a first flush uh in multiples or
whatever. I don't know, you know, and
then they're also growing second flushes
in the same room at the same time. Um,
yeah, if you're homogenizing it, it
needs to be uniform
and for the homogenization. So, it
whether it's first, second, or whatever,
I don't think is I think that doesn't
matter.
>> Dan, can I ask you a question?
>> Yes, please. Um, how often I think when
we talked you mentioned that sometimes
samples get sent back and need to be
rehomogenized. How often does that
happen?
>> Um, well, a manufacturer or grower,
whatever you want to call them, um, they
usually learn after the first or second
time. Um, and I they usually don't do it
again. So, it's like a uh it's usually
just a one-off and it not very often. I
really try to encourage people that, you
know, when you're a laboratory, if
you're going to sample it and if you're
required to sample it as a laboratory
and not allow the people to submit their
own samples, then the lab should, you
know, stir it or the manufacturer can
stir it really,
stir it again and then when we go to
take a sample, we stir it again and then
take a sample of it. Um, it's just
really hard with psilocybin because if
the homogenized product, if it's a large
quantity in a container, we've noticed
that the top, you know, quarter inch or
whatever starts to oxidize compared to
the bottom quarter inch of the
container. So, it will vary and you just
got to make sure that you constantly
homogenize it.
Thank you.
I
>> think Hannah has a comment. Do you want
to allow Hannah's mic, please?
>> Mic has already been enabled, Anna. So,
please begin when ready.
>> Yeah. So, um just going off of the first
person who commented, um since you
already got rid of the flushes, I'm just
looking at number four.
Um, does that mean we want to that does
that mean that y'all want to take out
any new flushes from a single
inoculation should be considered a new
batch?
>> Thank you, Hana. That was part of the
question that I had had is uh if we're
going with homogenizing, does one
through four just go away?
>> And that was what Dan was suggesting.
>> So,
>> yeah. So, what are your thoughts? Do you
think it just should go away that one
through four or just four?
>> I don't I think that's a lot to go away.
I like number one. That's really clear
and doesn't seem to be um on that topic
of flushing as the first two um
participants were speaking to. Um
I liked the idea of defining the weight.
I believe the last person spoke to
something about um creating a weight
definition in a batch. Um that seems
more simplified than um everything in
number three. And then
um
what I was wondering since you already
got rid of um that whole sentence about
flushes
um is keeping number four in
contradiction with that because um
because of what he spoke to with the
homogenization.
>> Yeah. I think if we if we get rid of the
flushing language, that'll be taken out
of the whole thing. And again, just for
context, I took Colorado's
recommendation in in its entirety. Um,
so
when we kind of update this in our
outline, you know, potency testing and
testing I think comes a little later in
the outline. We'll talk more about that,
but that'll certainly be in there. Um,
but if
uh let's let's go to James. Do you have
a comment, James?
Um,
yes. Am I unmuted here?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Thank you. So, just just to give
analogies as far as um uh for for folks
who haven't grown them before, um
imagine like growing tomatoes. you know,
say you had a a time limit whenever you
harvested. Some may be just right, some
may not be quite ripe enough. So, you
may harvest some that are ripe and ready
to go and then a few days later, a week
later, these are ready to go. Um, you
know, all coming from the same kind of
soil. Um, so again, with having the the
batch defined as what you know,
everything that is produced from the
substrate. Um, like I had commented
before, um, and and like you've heard a
lot, they're, uh, people who grow
mushrooms are very careful with
everything because it's so easy for just
natural mold and things in the air to
contaminate it. So, they will naturally
follow these processes where they won't
use the substrate for too long for the
potential of of a trike and and things
like that to happen. And also, different
strains um, do develop kind of at
different times. um the the flushes are
a lot different. Um but on average, you
know, maybe two weeks, maybe three weeks
at the very most, and then, you know,
that that substrate is done. Um testing
has already showed that you could have
two mushrooms uh from the same harvest,
from the same substrate who have some
pretty drastically different uh you
know, intensities of of psilocybin and
things like that. So having it where you
can basically do the whole harvest from
the substrate, homogenize everything
together, that's also going to make uh
kind of dosage and strength a lot more
accurate that way. Cuz if you have some
you produce that are higher, some that
are lower, having that average over the
whole harvest of one substrate um would
really make things a lot closer, you
know, as far as what growers produce and
things like that. So that that was all.
>> All right. So, it sounds like we have
most people um saying we should strike
the
flushing language or the flush language
from the batching definition. Is there
anybody in descent to that opinion that
wants to comment right now?
Okay, I think we can
go ahead with consensus on removing all
the the language around
you know um dividing the batches by
flushes.
Um next up I think let's go to our
weight. Is a kilogram a good weight
limit for a batch?
Okay. I'm not hearing or Oh, there we
go. We
>> We have a hand up. Yeah. Um,
please go ahead.
>> Thank you. Um, so what I'm curious about
here, um, and what I'm recalling from
one of the previous meetings that I
intended that I attended, which was a
board meeting. Um what stood out to me
in that meeting was um someone on the
board mentioned
this idea of making standards looser in
the beginning because it's easier to add
standards than to reverse a lot of
strict standards. And so I don't really
have like an opinion around the the
weight of a kilogram, but I guess I just
wanted to speak to
um my agreement and like promotion of
just creating really simple standards um
for us growers initially
um
because that it just it just really
resonated when she said that. So that
was it. Thank you.
>> I think we're trying to make things
simple as possible, but also I got to
recognize that there's a balance point
between also um
you know this has to be regulated to
some extent since it is in a medical
psilocybin content or context. So um
we're trying to keep things as open as
we can. Um we've struck a lot of
language out of a proposal so far but um
let's go to James see what you have to
say sir.
>> So uh I I guess my my first question and
then a comment and then and then I can
mute. Uh so my question uh would be what
is this weight um kind of limit
requirement um trying to accomplish or
trying to avoid happening? I'm kind of
curious about that. Uh, and then the
other comment I'll say is if it's 1
kilogram um after it's dried, uh, I I
believe if I Googled it correctly,
that's about 35 ounces. Um, that would
be an extremely large uh harvest from
from a batch. So that that number I
don't because I want to say mushrooms
are like 90% water or something or
thereabouts. So, whenever it's dried, so
that would be a very very almost like
commercial scale type of harvest if I'm
doing my math right. Uh, but I am kind
of curious again what's they're trying
to accomplish or avoid or whatever.
>> Okay. So,
>> Oh, go ahead.
>> A couple things on that. Uh, the
kilogram is just what Colorado used and
so that was kind of our starting point.
Um,
I'm skeptical that you can
adequately homogenize a batch larger
than that. I don't even know if you know
a kilogram like if you you were to take
several samples how how close it would
be. Maybe Dan can answer that question.
Um
but
I think we also need to balance like how
do we not weed out small-time growers?
You know, if you have a smaller grower
who's only producing
a half a pound and that's their batch
size and a larger one that's producing,
you know, five or 10 pounds in a in an
inoculation,
then the test, you know, if we allowed
no batch size limit, then the the
commercial scaled grower would have a a
massive advantage there. And also
the testing labs, you know, need to be
able to make enough profit on this to to
stay open. And we need we need both labs
and growers um around throughout the
state to keep this thing affordable, I
think. Um, and so we add a little bit of
cost to maybe a little extra testing on
smaller batch sizes, but that allows us
to have glower, growers, and testers
closer to the places where people need
it. It's kind of my thought process
right now. Um, but Dan, can you uh can
you go ahead and speak uh your mind
here?
>> Yes. Um, just like in the cannabis
industry, there are batch sizes. Um, and
it really comes down to um, you know,
some of these numbers are arbitrary.
People just picked them. And here in or
I think we're at 1 kilogram here in
Oregon, if I'm not mistaken, and
Colorado followed Oregon, and you guys
are following Colorado. So, it's kind of
the deal. Now, as a laboratory,
scientifically speaking, um, it is
definitely better to do smaller batches.
It's just easier to manage, handle, and
mix and stir and do whatever you need to
do for packaging. I mean, um, think
realistically how long is it going to
take to package this up, especially if
you guys are doing micro dose packaging.
Um, it could take multiple people
several days or a week to package. So,
it's what's really scientifically I
don't know what's manageable there. Now
as a lab we have to pull 5% of a batch.
So we end up taking that much material
um to be a representative sampling of
the batch
um you know so but yes it also comes
down to finances and it it really helps
the lab if there is some limit and uh
the larger the limit it's it's not
really in my opinion helping anybody.
Um, I don't know. Anything else? Any
other question? Did I answer it?
>> I think you answered it.
Did you have another comment on that or
was it Did we kind of cover that?
>> No, that's all. Um, it it should be
something. I worry about it getting too
large. Uh, you do you should define some
weight, but um I I don't know. It a
kilogram seems like it's fine. It could
be too much. I don't know. I'll let you
guys decide.
>> Yeah, I think you know somebody brought
up the 35 ounces.
It seems like a lot. So, who would be in
favor of of uh of shrinking that down to
maybe a half a kilo? And um let's go
ahead and take these comments first, but
kind of keep that in the back of your
mind and we'll kind of discuss that
after these comments. So, I've I've
enabled your mic. You may go ahead.
>> Thanks, Chris. Um Chris, I I understand
what you're saying and I agree with you
as far as the ecosystem
as it involves testing small growers and
potential commercial growers. I think we
should leave it at 1 kilogram and I
think you're going to probably further
define this as we get a little bit
further on to talk about testing so that
we're talking about what test is going
to be required per batch. So if we're
talking about one kilogram is going to
be equalized into requiring one test and
you know like the previous gentleman was
saying that you know that test is going
to require a set aside of 5%
of that initial batch. Um I think that
is probably adequate enough to make it
to where one kilogram is is the maximum
amount. So, it doesn't necessarily
affect the smaller growers any less.
It's just that uh it's going to be an
arbitrary number that we're just going
to have to pick. And if it's worked for
Oregon and for Colorado,
it doesn't sound like it's it's uh that
important in the grand scheme of things
other than making sure that it's
associated with the actual test
associated with the batch.
So I I see one inconsistency in here.
This is saying that this Colorado
language is saying they send 2.5 grams
in per kilo,
which would
not be
anywhere close to 5%, right? That would
be more like
um 1% or yeah,
a little more than 1%.
>> Yeah. And I'm I'm not saying that uh I'm
not saying that uh you know 5% is the
correct answer. I I think the you know
if we were looking at smaller samples,
it probably would be more beneficial as
far as the handling
um of the product, especially once it
gets into the testing. So because
there's a whole chain of custody process
that we still have to go through there
and I think the smaller the sample would
be the better easier way to track chain
of custody.
Okay.
I thought did we have another comment or
did somebody put their hand down there?
>> I believe James B. Um they had their
hand up.
>> Go ahead James.
>> Oh uh goodness. Sorry about that. I
thought I put it down. I was just typing
it in chat. Um, just that just some
rough rough math, you know, basically uh
1 kilogram of of dried mushrooms would
be about 175 lbs harvested because of
the amount of weight the mushrooms lose
80 they're 80 to 90% water. Um, so I
think that number is great. uh you know,
no non-commercial grower is going to
come close to getting to that amount
with uh um you know, so so that's
totally fine. Um the the 2.5 grams, I
was kind of seeing that as as you were
mentioning that um I think it would be
great, you know, one uh test per batch
as long as it's under the one kg. Um
then uh I I think that would be uh
totally adequate.
Let's go to James Brown.
>> Thanks, Chris. Um, I'm in support of if
you need to lower it, maybe go to two
grams for the total. Um, I I like the
one gram idea of just limiting it at
there for safety at this point. It would
it be harder for us to increase that?
That's how I just want to make sure that
we're not putting that cap on it and
then later on we'd have to go back and
say no, we need that a little bit more.
So, I just want to make sure I like the
one gram idea like you're saying. I just
want to make sure we don't cap that off
too early. Is is it should be one and a
half. I just want to make sure we we do
that right also. And I just want to make
sure we're all assuming over that 7-day
period, right? This is over dry. This is
going to be dried because if you get it
on the seventh day, it's still very
fresh.
weight's going to be different. Still
needs times to dry.
So, I just didn't I want to make sure
that it's the dried homogenized. Do we
need anything with that? And we're like
somebody said in the chat earlier about
dried versus wet. But if you harvest
over seven days, you will have a
variant. That's all. Thank you.
So, so just just to clarify for
everybody as we had already determined
that it would be dried um and the 7-day
period is as far as harvest. So, what
would be done? But that does bring up
the question about the 7-day period that
was recommended or that was a a comment
made earlier, but I don't think uh that
has been necessarily adopted or
anything. It's just there for the
conversation. Um, but if I may, um, we
have a lot of people actually just kind
of agreeing with the 1 kilogram. Is
there anyone who actually would have an
issue with the 1 kilogram?
>> Okay.
and and can we hear some of the reasons
for the the issue and the concern?
>> Let's go to Hannah.
>> Yes.
>> Um yes. So my uh reasoning on that is
I Okay, I'm hearing these numbers. This
weight
175 pounds of mushrooms. I just I just
did a journey with the tiniest amount
and like I'm just thinking like that's
so much and I really really value um
smallcale growing and like smallcale
organic farming and so I'm always going
to be in support of the smaller growers
and that's that's why I raised my hand.
I think that weight was was wet weight.
So that would be before they're they're
dried.
But let's go to Asher, please.
Yeah, sorry. This is Asher here. Um, I
guess I'm just kind of curious as to the
purpose of like the sizing of this
batching and and having limitations.
Like I mean I can understand maybe like
a maximum batch size but like what is
the reasoning to limit a smaller batch
size? Uh it just seems like it might
exclude some smaller growers. I'm just
curious.
>> So So Asher, this is the maximum. It it
batches can be smaller. It's just
batches up to 1 kilogram. So if someone
only had one uh you know had a batch
that was just um you know a quarter of a
kilogram, that would still be perfectly
fine. We're just trying to define that
upper limit.
>> Okay, understood. That wasn't clear to
me. That totally makes sense. Uh yeah,
in that case, that seems like a
reasonable size unless someone wants it
larger. But if they're submitting a
certain percentage of the batch for
testing, it shouldn't really matter too
much either way. Um unless there's
another reason to limit that upper size,
I'm not sure.
So that that's the I'm trying to protect
our smaller growers Asher by um by
limiting that batch size potentially.
Eric, would you Oh, I'm sorry. Asher,
did you have a question or another
comment?
>> Uh no, that's all. Thank you.
And Chris, just to clarify something
that so that two that 2.5 grams would
equate to um a quarter of a percent
just for a kilogram.
>> Yeah, maybe we can get Jan back in here
to
I I would recommend we hold off on what
the sample size is going to be. Um
because that there is an entire section
on that with regard to testing itself.
So I would say at this point if we could
just determine on the batches we've
actually already spent over half an hour
just on this item. So uh and we do have
a lot to cover over these next few
weeks. So um
>> okay let's uh let's hear from Eric real
quick and then we'll we'll I'll kind of
push this along I think.
Yep. Eric, nothing.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Eric has dropped off. All right.
So, um, let's see. All in favor? Oh,
there's Eric. Do you still want to talk,
Eric?
>> Uh, don't know what's happening there.
The hands seems to be going up and down
consistently. Uh, I have enabled your
mic. So, if you want to
attempt to say something, that's
okay.
We have Ben there with something to say.
Uh, Ben, have I been able to mic?
>> Oh, me. I
>> just quickly, I think we should take the
time limit off the 7-day period. I think
that'll actually support smaller growers
and being able to do two or three
flushes and still have a a batch and be
under that one kilogram. That's my
feedback.
>> Thank you, Ben. Right now, we're really
just talking about the size at the
moment.
The with the waiting period, I think
there's other people who have comments,
but if we could get a determination as
far as the size, I think that would
help. Let's go ahead and if you are
wanting to lower the size from a
kilogram, please raise your hand.
I'm only seeing one person. So, I'm
gonna say that we have a consensus to
keep the
weight at 1 kilogram for a batch.
Um,
and just to confirm, I I did only see
one hand raised there, right?
>> That is correct. Okay. So, we'll keep it
at a kilogram.
Uh, for the next part, I I guess we
could go on to time with that.
I I feel like there was already kind of
consensus through this process that
there's no reason that to limit it to 7
days because
uh we're homogenizing it anyway. So,
multiple flushes is not an issue. is
does anybody have dissent to that
opinion?
Okay.
Um, seeing no hands, I'm going to assume
that we should remove the language
around the seven days too. Should we put
a limit on the time limit between when
uh something can be and I kind of think
we need to define it at some point
because we we will probably need to be
able to retest at at a certain point
after it's tested the first time. So
would three weeks be a reasonable
timeline limit to catch uh a batch
Any
comments on that?
>> We're seeing uh two comments in the
chat. One by Adrian, one by James. Both
arguing we got three now. Um all arguing
four weeks,
>> four weeks.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> We have a comment here as well from
Gregory Evans saying that there is a
massive variance in flush uh caden cad
cadence cadence. Oh my gosh. Uh, and
then, uh, Dan Houston, there needs to be
a time limit, he stipulates. And, uh,
James, you have your hand up, so please
begin when ready.
>> Um, yeah, just, uh, I I think four weeks
is good. Like some of the others have
stated, the different species, um, you
know, harvest, flush, uh, in different
amount of time, some quicker, some
slower, and then there's also variance
on, you know, humidity and temperature,
and there's just so many factors. Um,
but yeah, I I think I agree with
everybody that four weeks would pretty
much cover all the bases for all the
different strains that I'd be grown.
>> Okay. Is there anybody in descent to
putting a four-week timeline on it?
All right. I'm going to go ahead and say
that we have consensus around a Oh,
sorry, John. Do you have something to
say? Go ahead.
>> Um, I was under the assumption that we
were going to be doing all solicites.
Um, and if we are, some of them take
longer to fruit for a second flush. So,
if we limit that, then
they you wouldn't be able to get a
second flush.
Yeah, I I'm feeling like more than four
weeks might be a little
a little long long.
Yeah, if we go four months,
some of Colorado and Oregon, I think are
testing at retesting at six and nine
months
and I think Dan did a paper on this. How
often are you seeing the batches get
retested, Dan?
>> Yeah, D saying four weeks. It seems too
long.
>> Four weeks seems a little long for a
batch. Uh but I'm you know it's you got
to decide. Um uh we've seen potency
change over time but the total
equivalent psilocybin has not changed.
Um so that really needs to be taken in
consideration. And when you guys do have
have retests done, um maybe think about
and and and I'm I'm I'm worried about
some of the things I say, but think
about um if they're not happy with the
test lab or test results and another
laboratory is issuing higher results,
you would encourage lab shopping by
allowing them to retest a batch at any
lab they wanted to. So maybe think about
making, you know, stick to the whatever
lab for that batch um for retesting and
stuff like that. But uh here in Oregon,
um we're not really allowed to retest
product.
>> Okay, I misspoke on that. Sorry.
>> Colorado does, if I'm not mistaken.
And the only reason Oregon doesn't is
because they don't want to encourage lab
shopping. But I tried to fight Oregon on
that. I think it should be retested.
>> Yeah, I think it should be retested too.
Um especially in a medical context and I
think four months seems a little long.
Um
let's go let's let's uh
let's start with a a month.
Who is in favor or who is opposed to a
month?
Please raise your hand.
At present, there are no hands raised.
>> There are no hands raised. Okay.
All right. So, we have consensus then.
If you don't speak up, then things are
not going to roll the way you want them
to. I encourage everybody to to please
um
you know speak in opposition if you
disagree, but I think a month is a
reasonable time to collect a batch and
uh we'll probably have some sort of
retest at at 9 months
um when we get to that point. But
uh does that answer all of our questions
surrounding a batch? Is there anything
else that we need to define or put in
there
as
um to kind of lock that down?
>> I think that's good as far as the badge
portion. And I know um the next set goes
into testing, but we do have to talk
about the sunset claws
um and uh uh and go forward. and Eric,
we are actually reading the chats and
have been making some comments regarding
those and listening to them. Um, we're
just not lead reading them aloud because
the conversation has pretty much
mimicked what has been in the chat just
with uh other areas and we want to make
sure that we are getting things moving
forward uh as much as we can. So, uh,
just with regard to that, but, um, if
Estebon is fully able to be in the
meeting, I would suggest we go to the
sunset clause next.
>> Sounds good to me.
>> Estebon, are you able to be here to
speak?
>> Yes, I am, Dominic. Thank you.
>> Okay, perfect. I will switch documents.
Give me just a moment and I'll pull
yours out of
>> All right.
But if you'd like to start speaking on
it while I find which of my 6,000
windows I have open is actually the
sunset closet.
>> Certainly. Yeah. So, uh, as a reminder
or perhaps new information to folks just
joining us, uh, for the first time, uh,
we've been discussing a sunset clause
across a variety of different
committees, uh, regarding the Silicon
Advisory Board, um, with the idea of
providing both equity and access to New
Mexico residents and also, uh, complying
with, uh, constitutional law. Uh, this
whole concept of a sunset clause in
regard to a SI assignment program is not
new. It's something that's previously
been practiced in various medical
cannabis scenes across the country and
most recently in the Oregon psilocybin
program. Uh the sunset clause as noted
at the top here is a statute or
regulation or other law uh that
essentially puts an end date on any
given measure here. So the idea is for
the first few years of program
inception, this program can only be only
accept licenses from New Mexico
residents. Uh the big reason for this
president is to stop uh multi-state
organizations and larger venture capital
from coming in and monopolizing, you
know, what is intended to be a program
to truly support New Mexico residents.
Uh if we scroll down just a little bit
here, uh the president, we do have the
exact wording from the Oregon Psilocybin
Services Statute on there. Um they note
essentially you know very similar to
language to what I've created below uh
in that the first two years of program
participation are limited to uh either
individuals or businesses owned by a
majority uh or with a majority ownership
of a resident uh by at least 50% for the
first two years of program inception.
So again this just goes to show there is
absolutely precedent for applying uh a
clause such as this. uh we wouldn't
necessarily be breaking any new ground,
but I think it does really serve to
protect those with a true interest here
within the state of New Mexico. So, if
you want to scroll down to the proposed
measure, uh this is sort of my initial
draft here. And I will say I think we're
all very open to to discourse on
changing any of the specific metrics in
here, whether that's time frames or
limitations on ownership percentage. Uh
so by all means please feel free to
comment or raise your hand to apply any
sort of uh notes you may have on this.
So the applicability of this measure it
applies to all applicants and holders of
licenses under the New Mexico Department
of Health medical psilocybin program. Um
I put a cursory list up here. This will
definitely need to be updated to
whatever the final license categories
are. Um as I saw it it was
manufacturers, testing facilities and
facilitators. Um, Dominic, are there any
other licenses beyond these three
categories that y'all are looking at?
>> Um, not at this current time.
>> Okay, wonderful. So, that seems to be
good news.
>> I'm sorry. Actually, Estan, let me take
that back. There is the possibility when
we get into the idea of transportation,
but again, as you mentioned, we can
update it if there are other uh permits
and and licenses that are issued.
>> Absolutely. Okay. Thank you.
So, being a quote unquote sunset clause,
you know, there is a temporary
requirement in place here. Uh, so
non-withstanding any other provisions of
law um until January 1st, 2029, any
applicant for a license subject to this
measure must demonstrate compliance with
residency and ownership requirements set
forth here. Uh the individual applicant,
so for example, an individual therapy
practitioner uh who is working at a
facilitator location. Uh if they are an
individual, they must provide proof that
they have been a resident of the state
of New Mexico for a minimum of 24 months
immediately preceding the date of the
application. Uh so that's just two full
years of residency leading up to the
application date. Uh for entities, which
would be the larger majority of
applicants for licenses, uh this would
include corporations, LLC's,
partnerships, associations, trusts, all
of our, you know, legal umbrella of
commercial entities. Uh for ownership
requirements uh we're looking at more
than 51% ownership uh ownership interest
that is in the applicant must be held by
individuals who have been a resident of
the state of New Mexico. Same sort of
time frame here minimum of 24 months
immediately preceding the date of
application. Uh similarly uh control
requirements. This is sort of designed
to prevent what we may consider a shell
corporation right like someone has a
cousin that lives here and they use
their name to apply for a license. uh
the individual described in se
subsection A must possess actual
authority to direct management policy
and operations of the applicant. Uh that
would be the business itself whether
through voting rights, management
authority, contractual rights or other
indisha of control as determined by the
department of health. Um I do know the
department of health has a uh your own
legal team available there. So I wanted
to leave this language a little bit more
open and subject to uh the department of
health scrutiny.
Going down to our next clause here,
anti-ircumvention,
essentially honoring the spirit of this
measure here.
So, the New Mexico Department of Health
may deny any application, refuse
renewal, or take disciplinary action if
determined that an ownership,
management, financial, or contractual
agreement has been established for the
purpose of evading or circumventing the
requirements of this measure. Again,
just ensuring that we're honoring the
spirit of this and we don't allow any
technicalities to flip through that I
may have missed in, you know, the the
measures and uh individual sections
listed above.
And finally, measure duration. Uh the
measure would be set to expire January
1st, 2029. Uh on or after this date,
there will be no ownership, residency,
or local participation requirements
unless expressly authorized by the
Department of Health. Um, again, if we
find that New Mexico based businesses
are meeting all of the needs of not only
production side, but also serving the
end users or the patients in this case,
uh, I really don't see any need to
actually permanently end it. So, there
is an option for theoretical renewal,
whether that's a temporary renewal
period or an indefinite renewal period.
The language here is intended to be very
open because it's hard for all of us to
predict where our program is going to be
in about two years.
So again, all of these dates, all of
these time frames, I am extremely open
to any thoughts, criticisms, ideas from
any of y'all here. Um, particularly New
Mexico residents, as unless you are a
New Mexico resident, you do not
currently have a voting right in this
meeting.
>> Selena, we have a hand up there by James
Brown.
>> Go ahead, James.
>> Do you want to go ahead?
Um, I just wanted to say I'm in support
of something like this. My only
suggestion would be to Is there a way to
make it 36 months? The reason why
>> Absolutely.
>> Yeah.
>> is be there's because we're in rural
communities, you know, and those those
uh it's going to have it's going to be
really slow and I'm just afraid those
people won't have the opportunity to own
their businesses long enough in those
rural communities to really get a foot
going. uh with the other businesses I've
done and pharmacy land, it takes two to
three years in general just for us to
get there. So, I can just imagine, you
know, going through the city council,
you know, doing everything else you have
to do just to get this thing going. Uh
there's going to be some precedent
setting and I would just that that would
be my thing would be open at the 36 for
us and then, you know, like with that
option clause, I like it.
So to be honest, I think finding the
ceiling here is going to be something
that's open for discussion. I mean, to
be perfectly honest, my preference would
be to close this program to New Mexico
residents permanently, but I think a
sunset clause has to be sort of our
jumping off point to establish
president. So does anybody else have a
higher ceiling than 36 months?
See? Okay, so no hands or comments
currently. So yeah, I think 36 months is
absolutely reasonable and you are
correct, especially in a rural setting,
you know, where not only do you have
less access to, you know, the resources
to develop your licensed business, but
also probably face more scrutiny from
local lawmakers or regulations of your
city, county, um, or municipality. Uh, I
would say 36 months seems extremely
fair, which would place that at July
1st, 2029.
Is there any opposition to a 36month
sunset or uh expanding this to 36 months
for a sunset clause?
Okay, I think we can do that by
consensus. Is there any critiques,
criticisms about any of the language in
this
measure?
All right. All right. I think this is
kind of an important one. So, I would
like to ask for a vote on it. So, all in
favor of
um
for this measure, please raise your
hands.
Okay. And we are at 15 in counting. So,
uh that's already more than half the
people who are here. So,
>> hey, please lower your hands everyone.
>> And then as always, I want to give room
for dissent. Does anybody descent to
this proposal?
>> Hold on just a minute, Chris. We still
have people with their hands up. Um
>> and go ahead, Chris. All right. Does
anybody desent to this proposal? Please
raise your hand.
All right. Seeing none, I'm going to
accept this sunset clause as uh proposed
by Estavon
as a proposal to make to the advisory
board. Thank you so much, Estebon, for
your work putting that together. Um,
>> absolutely. Thank you. uh Chris as well
as uh you know the whole Department of
Health team and everyone involved in
this meeting. It seems like we're all
really in agreeance on protecting this
program as a benefit for all New Mexico
residents.
>> Excellent. And Dominic, what what do you
think the best should we uh have this as
a separate document that we just take to
the advisory board or are we going to
put this language into our
outline? How do you feel like we should
do that? Yeah, I don't think we need to
do the entire document, but we will
include the document as supporting
information and you know supporting uh
evidence essentially. Um but we'll
actually what we'll do from the program
standpoint is we'll distill it into a
couple of one lines because what we
really just need for the board is you
know is the sunset clause with that
expiration date to ensure that it's New
Mexico residents um and of like the 51%.
So we can reduce it down into that
language. Um the thing to remember is
regulations end up being really long to
begin with and so we have to try to
minimize the language and we are working
with one of our uh department of health
attorneys to take the information and
turn it from the outline and the
information that is being agreed upon
here to turn that by the time we get to
regulatory stand uh to turn it into that
regulation language. So, a lot of what
we're doing now is we're we're really
making the um the consensus and the
votes about the ideas and then the
language itself will get finalized uh to
make sure that it's in the correct legal
form. Um because believe it or not, a
comma or a that or some other things
makes a huge difference in it and we
want to make sure that we are doing this
in the right way. So, that's why we
don't need to worry so much about the
specifics here. we just bring it to uh
quite frankly to the attorneys and there
are some attorneys that are here on this
meeting and once we do have that
language it will be shared and there'll
be there's a whole set of public
meetings that actually happen just
around that language on rules and
regulations. So uh that will happen
after the board has made their
recommendations just to sort of clarify
that for people who are not familiar
with the process.
Thank you, Dominic. I think Hannah uh I
apologize if I'm saying your wrong name
wrong. Uh is it
Please go ahead and make your comment
and correct me if I'm saying your name.
>> It's Hana. Yeah, it's Hana with a soft
A. Thanks for asking. Um yeah. Um, so I
thought we were just focusing
on that whole vote just um that decision
around that that um extension on the
timeline that 36-month timeline. So, I
just did I had two things um actually I
just want to speak to one of them um on
um the New Mexico resident requirement
um which says two years on there right
now um I've been a New Mexico resident
for many many years since gosh like 20
over 20 years and I witnessed um during
COVID a ton of influx
of people from California. Um, and so I
just I love the spirit of long-term New
Mexico residents and I would like to
suggest that we
extend the date to be before COVID
because um there was a big impact um on
our community like for unaffordable
housing and just like there was a big
negative impact that I'm really
witnessing here um because of the influx
of people from California and I'm sorry
that I'm so emotional about it, but I
really care about affordable housing.
And that really went down when we had
people from California come in. And I
just don't know if they have that same
New Mexico spirit. And so I just wanted
to name that. Thank you.
>> All right. Um, Hana, I appreciate your
comment and um, but unfortunately we've
already voted on it and I have to honor
the spirit of that democratic process.
Um, so please don't hold your comments
back prior to uh, if I'm not being clear
on what we're voting for, I'll work on
that in the future. Um, but yes, I think
we need to move on to the next section.
>> Dominic, can you uh
>> Yeah, I'm pulling it up now, Chris.
>> I'm sorry.
>> No, no, you're good. It just takes a
moment. Um,
okay. And should have the document open
now.
Uh, can people see it? Chris, can you
see it at this point? I'm hoping you
can.
>> I still can't. I don't know.
>> Other people.
>> Okay, other people are able to see it.
So, I don't know what's happening there,
Chris. Um,
okay. So the next set we actually had
already spoken previously about the
homogenization
was going to be with regard to testing
authority and that the testing uh let me
actually just put this little bit on in
um
the chat. Sorry everybody and takes me a
moment.
Okay. And what we have is that the
testing would be performed by department
approved laboratories. Uh and then
requirements for laboratories to be
approved. Some of the recommendations
that have already come in through public
comments and through other areas. And
again, we're including these in not
necessarily because it's coming from the
department, but because these are items
that have been recommended um by various
people is to utilize the existing
cannabis testing laboratories. they
would have to submit their uh their SOPs
and their IDC's, which Dan could
probably uh explain better than I can
what an IDC actually is, but it
essentially is uh that they have
verified their ability to perform that
test. Um and the so that's their
processes for extracting the samples. Um
some other recommendations have been to
utilize the ISO and the IEC 17025
accredited labs. Um and then other labs
that are either approved or overseen by
the department. That last one actually
is one rec as far as for the department
because that includes the state
laboratory for example
which actually has that accreditation
and so that was why that was there. Um,
another one that has come in, um, that
since this was originally written was
actually, um, that not necessarily
existing cannabis testing laboratories,
but laboratories that meet the same
standards as are currently in the
cannabis regulations as far as for them
to become permitted. So, if it was a
laboratory that did not want to be a
cannabis testing lab, but they met all
those other qualifications otherwise as
far as their certifications, processes
for cleaning the lab, all of that sort
of thing, that then they could have a
process to be approved as well without
going through the cannabis testing
process or the cannabis permitting
process.
>> Uh, excellent.
Um, I got a quick question for you,
Dominic. Are all the marijuana or
cannabis labs currently
um ISO certified? Is that how you guys
run it?
>> Uh, no, they are not. They have a whole
set of regulations that they have to
meet. Um,
>> okay. So, we don't have
Well, that opens up. Dan, can I call on
you to talk about certifications and
what we might want to require for our
our labs?
>> Um, sure. Um, I personally believe that
if you're testing for uh psilocybin and
or even cannabis, you should be required
to have an accreditation from a third
party accreditation company such as the
uh ISO7025
and or um NEAC uh NLEC or NEACTNI
um because
that third party third party
accredititors they oversee the
laboratories and if there's nobody
overseeing laboratories
um there has been a history of
laboratories um maybe cutting corners
and doing things they're not supposed to
be. Plus, if this is a medicine,
especially a psychedelic medicine, and
somebody is not is wanting to do micro
doing or less dose and have a
subperceptual dose, um I would hope that
that laboratory could do good and
accurate testing. Um, we've already done
some round robins, which mean with
others psilocybin testing labs across
the United States, and we have some good
data on that that I think I've shared
with, um, New Mexico already, but u
maybe if I haven't, just let me know.
I'll share it. And then uh how abs are
not all equal and you know we had one
lab that was testing at three or four
times the potency of the other
laboratories. So somebody would have
been not getting an adequate amount of
dosage if they were using this
laboratory. Um so I just I don't know. I
believe it's necessary. You have it in
pharmaceutical.
uh you hopefully have it for
environmental and water quality and all
of that stuff. So I it it should follow
suit. Um, in my opinion, the NEAC and
TNI standards are a little bit more
stringent and they focus on um they
focus on the raw data and making sure
that the data coming off of the
instruments is good, valid, and
acceptable versus the and this is a
general statement um and versus the
ISO7025
is more of a is your paperwork in order
um and not as much with is the equipment
running correctly.
and are you able to see the stuff in the
equipment or the in the run? So, it's a
little different of a a certification
accreditation, but it still is something
better than nothing. And labs have a
history of um not doing the right thing
if they're not accredited.
>> Thank you, Dan. I appreciate your
perspective on that. Um, and let's go to
Shane.
>> Yeah. Uh, this question is for Dan. Um,
is there a requirement for calibration
of of the tools in the accreditation
process? I mean, is is it once a year?
Is it I mean, or is it just at your own,
you know,
whim? I mean, I've seen in the past um
labs that don't have any requirements on
um calibrations and then the tools get
out of cal and they're providing bad
information and there's nothing there to
um regulate that they get them
calibrated at any specific rate and
therefore the whole thing is pretty much
invalid.
Well, um, to speak on that, basically
that's where, uh, Oregon, we we went
with the TNI, NEAC, which is
environmental, water quality, and all of
that. And the only reason we did that
was because uh us labs in the cannab in
the beginning of the cannabis industry
all banned together and we were helping
writing the laws and we thought that
Oregon since they this the Oregon health
authority is a accrediting body for NEAC
TNI um that they would be willing to
work with us more. So we went down that
road. The rest of the states went with
uh ISO. Um what and what I've feel like
is happening um with the ISO is it's not
again not as ar as a stringent on the
equipment and the calibrations and all
of that as the other accreditation. And
yes, I've seen labs
not calibrate or do what they need to,
but if you validate and do everything
you're supposed to be be doing and
passing your proficiency testing as a
laboratory, then you're good to go. The
problem here in psilocybin is is there's
really not much to deal with in
proficiency testing. So, no labs,
including mine, have really participated
in a proficiency testing program, which
means it's been written in the law that
we're not really required to unless a
system comes in place. Um, but that's
where I've taken the liberty and
contacted every psilocybin lab I've
known across the states and we've all
created a round robin and we all want to
do the right thing and produce adequate
and not tarnish this industry because
this industry is valid and important to
me. Um, I don't know. I probably got on
a tangent. Sorry.
So then maybe we add into the
documentation even if it's uh even if we
if we go with ISO or NEAC that there
that there is a you know once a year uh
requirement for recal to make sure that
the tool is measuring properly because
like you just said earlier there was one
lab you I think it was you that said
that there was evidently their tool was
out of calibration so and they were
producing different results than anybody
else. we can't have that, right? Or we
don't that's that's not a good
situation.
>> It's definitely not a good situation.
And the problem here in psilocybin, what
we found in Oregon and Colorado, and you
guys will soon find out, the volumes are
not there. So, you're not going to have
a lot of laboratories. You're going to
be lucky if you have one laboratory
wanting to do it, um, or more than one.
Um, the other issue is is Colorado has
some amazing psilocybin laboratories.
Uh, I know them personally, hung out,
we've talked at events, and they were
all ready to get licensed, but Colorado
wrote into the law that they could no
longer test for anybody that was not
licensed. So, I know very good quality
laboratories that said, "No, thank you."
And I then this laboratory that is doing
the testing now I don't really know
anything about them really. Um which is
kind of weird. Um and they're the one
and only laboratory in Colorado. So and
I'm the one and only laboratory in
Oregon. So definitely and whether it's
proficiency testing and here in Oregon
we have to do proficiency testing twice
a year. Um and I think Colorado is once
a year. Most states are once a year. So
once or twice a year definitely pro
provi part participate in some sort of
PT proficiency test. Um there is one out
there but it's button mushrooms and they
spike it with psilocybinosin and you
read it off of that which I guess is
close. It's better than nothing. Um
yeah, so definitely that and make sure I
mean you should be calibrating if you're
a good quality laboratory you want to
calibrate regularly because you should
be noticing drop offs uh with the
equipment over time because of the
columns um get plugged and clogged or
dirty.
>> Thank you Dan.
Um,
so I have got a couple thoughts on this.
I think we should go switch from the ISO
to the NEAC accreditation.
Um, being that that's more
scientifically supported as Dan uh said
and it it's less focused on the
paperwork and more on the
instrumentation being validated.
And correct me if I'm saying anything
incorrectly, Dan.
>> I would just caution I would caution
that I would do a little investigation
with New Mexico and are there TNI NEAC
accredited labs there and how can you or
whatever. But I also want to caution
just because if you're only going to end
up with one lab and they're a cannabis
lab, well, did you say your cannabis
labs are not accredited under ISO?
>> They are not necessarily under ISO. It's
not a requirement. They do have to go
through their own process and it does
include submitting the IVC's and the
SOPs.
>> Oh, okay.
>> And they do have to do uh proficiency
testing. I'm not sure if it's annually
currently or more often, but it is at a
minimum annually.
>> Okay. Well, I I encourage an
accreditation. I I
I I just encourage it just because it's
a third body that comes in and audits uh
every year andor every other year and
actually makes people dig through their
paperwork and they walk through the
laboratory and they make sure that
people aren't don't have unlabeled
bottles and blah blah blah and don't
have sticky notes and this or that
everywhere. So it I don't know. I just
believe that's my belief something. Yes.
A and Dan, just to be clear, that is
actually part of what does happen with
the cannabis testing labs is they do get
that inspection that is done through the
regulation. Uh well, it used to be done
through Department of Health, so through
this program and and in conjunction with
the state lab and is now done through
the cannabis control division.
>> Okay, that's good. Well, some
something's happening, so that's good.
>> Yeah,
>> I'm sorry. Keep going about the
accreditation. Go for it.
>> And Dan, I just had a quick question. I
want to make sure that I've got the
correct initials. It's NVLAP,
correct?
Is what you're discussing.
>> I'll put it in the chat.
>> Okay, perfect. Thank you.
Okay. Um,
yeah. And did I did I post the right
link above that, Dan? Is that correct
to their web page?
>> The link. What are you talking about?
>> Oh, I I see that chat, Chris.
>> There's a chat to the NEAC Institute.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay. Yeah, that looks like that's
Yep, that's it.
>> Okay, that I was hoping so because
that's where I've been kind of reading
from. Um,
so that would be my recommendation is
that we we ensure accreditation given
the nature of this process. Um, Dan
has been doing this for a while. So I I
think
that might be prudent. Um are there any
comments against or
um in support of something else?
Do you have a thought process on this,
Dominic?
Uh the only thing that I would say as
far as with existing cannabis testing
laboratories is it actually speaks to
Dan's point as far as how difficult it
can be for a laboratory to start up and
uh to be able to sustain especially as a
program is just starting. Um and one of
the things is is these laboratories as
we were mentioning they do already while
it may not necessarily be other
accreditation do go through uh that
those walkthroughs and those um you know
going through that testing process as
far as with RLD and so they do have that
third party that's looking at them to
ensure that they're keeping up
standards. Um, and what it does is
because some of these others actually
have fairly high costs on them, it also
makes it a little bit more reasonable.
Um, and they are already currently New
Mexico businesses. And so that's another
uh another side for it, which doesn't
mean that we cannot have other labs as
we were talking about that come in who
do one of the other thirdparty
accreditations, whether it be the ISO,
IEC, or the NEAC. um and uh going
through that uh just needing to ensure
that they do indeed go through
proficiency testing uh on an annual
basis regardless of who they are.
All right, let's uh let's go to Brett.
All right, thanks guys. Can you hear me?
Okay, Chris.
Okay. Um, great. Yeah. So, I was just
going to say kind of along what what
Dominic said, you know, I think leaving
more options rather than less in regards
to that. Um, where it's kind of an
eitheror. Um and if the if the
department is you know if the department
feels comfortable that they would have
the the resources and capability for
them to you know for them to certify it.
Um I I think that would even that would
even work. you know that kind of there's
three options or yeah the two that the
two different certifications you had
talked about or just independent
certification through um through RLD or
Department of Health whoever that is but
if the state has that um I think you
know if we're trying to get if we're
trying to encourage um businesses to to
get into this I think allowing more
options rather than less um would would
you know the the more options we can
give people would be better And I I
would totally support, you know, I I
don't want to create things for DO to
have to do or the state to have to do if
they're not comfortable with it, but I
would say if they're, you know, if they
feel good about they can send people in
to say it meets our certifications, um
that seems like it would would cover it
in a way that would be more economically
feasible for a lot of businesses. So
that's that's my two cents on it.
>> Thank you, Brett.
Oh, and sorry, I thought my hand I
thought I was putting my hand down. I
realized I just put it back up, so I
didn't have anything else to say.
>> Excellent. Let's go to uh Greg.
Just adding a making sure my mic works
here.
Okay. Um, just adding a question about
would any of these national
accreditation processes
increase scrutiny on an existing
cannabis lab going into testing
psilocybin? Like is have we analyzed and
asked all those questions? Um, I'm
assuming many people have. I just kind
of want to put that into the sphere of
the conversation. And then additionally,
it to what Brett was just saying, can we
use the scientific laboratory division
that we have to leverage any sort of
um
you know uh early acceptance as we
figure out what the landscape is moving
into the first year or two of the
program.
So, thank you, Greg. Those are good
questions. Um, we haven't seen that with
regard to uh the other accreditations,
you know, potentially creating other
issues for the cannabis testing labs.
Um, and not just here, but other places.
That's something that's come up uh many
times in in many different states as
they do that. That doesn't necessarily
mean that it can't. We are talking about
schedule one substances. So uh what the
federal government does is outside our
purview. Um but um the the other aspect
of that is SLD is actually acts as our
reference laboratory. Um so that they
can actually then do other tests that
may be needed if there are problems. For
example, say that a laboratory has done
a test um and says there's and I'll just
use an example that of what happens in
cannabis uh and there's mold on the
product uh or or they show no mold but
then later there ends up being mold then
SLD ends up being that reference
laboratory to be able to help with some
of those double checks uh to be able to
do that. And so because of that they
have to stay independent um but are
there for uh if there are issues with
contaminants for example the lab will do
things where products will end up with
um say uh we just had a there was a
health alert that went out with regard
to raw milk and lististeria for example.
So that's where the state lab comes into
play as the reference laboratory
just as an example. Um and then in the
chat there is a question about border
control and yes Eric that is um so
product is not going to be able to go
through border patrol. That actually is
something that happens currently with
cannabis. It will not be any different
with regard to psilocybin. Um, we do
educate people that they need to make
sure that if they are cultivating south
of the checkpoints or also uh east of
the checkpoints depending where in the
state they are that they are actually
ensuring that they are uh testing at a
laboratory there. And so for example,
one of the current labs actually for
cannabis actually has testing facilities
in both Los Cruus and in Albuquerque for
exactly that reason.
And that, by the way, is one of the
other reasons for why uh being able to
permit or uh the current existing
cannabis testing laboratories could be
beneficial because of that geography
issue with border patrol and the border
checkpoints.
I hope that helps.
Yeah.
Okay. Um,
so you're confident that we can do it
with existing. So let me ask you this.
How do we if we need
if we need to do secondary samples from
labs in that kind of cordoned off zone
with border patrol checkpoints? How do
we work that?
>> Uh, we have figured out different ways.
If if it's okay, I'll leave it at that
at the moment.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's fine. That's fine.
Okay. When there's a will, there's a
way. I got you.
Um,
so we'd probably be kind of operating
under that same
um
set of assumptions, right? And and just
so everybody also is aware, I mean, this
isn't just a suddenly if they're a
cannabis lab, we would permit them. They
would still have to go through a review
process. They would have to request the
permit. They still would have to show
their capability to be able to test
psilocybin. So, it's not it wouldn't be
something that they would just
automatically receive.
What about a
requirement to to have them do like a
roundroin testing, you know, maybe twice
a year to make sure that we're
accurately
Yeah, that that is something that we
actually have been talking about as we
talk about what actually goes into the
testing itself. That is a requirement as
part of the proficiency is having it
tested by another laboratory. And that's
also in part where SLD would come into
play.
>> Okay. So, so I'm I getting ahead of
myself. We need to focus back on this.
>> No, no, that's a great qu that's a great
question.
>> Okay.
Did somebody else have a comment?
Um,
so where's everybody at on
accreditation? Do we think the state
under what it's currently doing with
cannabis is
a good enough accreditation for this
this program? Um,
let me see a show of hands. Who thinks
we should go with the current state
program
and Chris I would um I would also say
that it's that or going through the
third party ensuring they have the third
party accreditation.
>> Yeah, that was kind of my plan after we
we get a idea here. Okay. So, how many
hands do we have? Do we have three
>> at present? Three hands. Full hands.
So,
>> um I'm sorry. I saw my thing was still
unmuted. I wanted to be clear. So, this
is only So, Chris, can I guess before we
can you lay out what the options are
before we actually vote on the on the
three because I'm in support of the more
rather than just that. I just wanted to
include that.
I think there's maybe a little confusion
on what exactly we're we're voting to
support. Thanks for stopping me on that,
Brett, so we get everybody up to speed.
Okay, so right now we have two options.
We we kind of run this program as
cannabis is running it through the the
Department of Health's process for
cannabis and we we'll kind of follow
that model and their what they're doing
or we require the NEAC or ISO
accreditation the third party and we can
we can vote on that separately which
we're what we're going to go with
afterwards. Um,
and is there a third option that I'm I'm
not thinking of at this time?
>> Chris, I would just say that it's it's
we're really from from the standpoint of
the program, we actually are
recommending that the labs be one or the
other. So, not to limit it to either the
current existing cannabis testing labs
or the other third party, but to allow
for both.
So a lab could either be uh apply uh as
they would as an existing cannabis
testing laboratory or they can get the
third party certification
um such as the NEAC or the ISO and they
could go through either of those
pathways to become a psilocybin testing
laboratory.
>> Okay. So that would be the the third
option that they can do either.
>> Correct.
>> Okay. So, um,
my do we have a let me give a couple
minutes for comments here on this before
we we start going ahead. So, let's go
ahead to Eric.
Eric, your mic has been enabled.
Okay.
We have Gregory Evans next. Um,
go ahead.
>> Um, I just wanted to take a moment to
confirm the user stories um, in plain
language um, as I'm understanding
they're being presented. So, one, I am a
New Mexico cannabis lab
and I can use my existing platform to
say, "Hey, I want to test for
psilocybin. These are the parameters
that I need to meet and then I get that
accreditation and we can move forward."
User story two, I am not a cannabis lab,
but I want to start a lab. I go through
the set processes of um ISO or NEAC
accreditation,
fill out my application to the
Department of Health, and then I am just
a psilocybin testing lab or I'm a an
existing cannabis lab and I want to
boost my reliability, I can also get
accredited
and
um
use that as a way to differentiate
myself in the market. Is that correct?
Am I missing any possible path?
>> No. No, Greg. It just it's not that the
third party accreditation would outside
of the current state level would not be
required for the cannabis either way.
cannabis laboratories can go and get
that third party um if they wish
regardless. The question is
>> the question is
>> do do we go with just the existing
cannabis testing laboratory pathway
or go with the AC third party
accreditation pathway or allow for both.
So those are the three different
pathways. So either I think it's
important
I think it's important to allow for both
that but I'll yield.
>> Did you want to finish your comment,
Dominic?
>> Yeah, I was just saying those are the
three choices I think as we have them
now. Either existing testing cannabis
testing laboratories, third party
accreditation or both allowed.
>> All right, I'm trying to think about the
best way to do this. Let's go with um
who thinks that both pathway pathways
should be allowed. Raise your hands
please.
>> We have 11 present.
>> 11 hands up. Okay. Please put your hands
down.
So that that's already probably a
majority, but who thinks uh there should
just be a third party
accreditation
only
>> and no hands, right? Oh, we have one. We
have one hand.
>> Uh although Don, you had raised your
hand on the previous one. Is this a
comment that you wanted to make?
>> I didn't know that there I thought they
were separate. I didn't know that they
were about the same thing.
>> Yeah.
>> So, delete the my second uh handout.
>> Great. All right. Thank you, Tom.
>> Okay. And so the other option would just
be having it done under the the current
um
cannabis pathway. Who thinks it should
only be done that way? Right.
All right. I think we've got a
unanimous vote for seeing no no hands on
that last option. I'm going to say we
have a unanimous vote for a process
where labs can either use the existing
cannabis testing process or become
certified through
NEAC or ISO. Now, do we want to uh allow
for both of those or should we restrict
restrict it to one or the other?
Um, does anybody have comment on whether
we should restrict
to NEAC or ISO?
Great.
I would like some time to do research on
other uh accredit accreditidation
pathways to see if there is
you know costbenefit analysis or pathway
and access and equity that can be
considered in any of those. Um but I
think if we asterisk the AC
accreditation pathway uh to be defined
in the final draft um I would I would
just I just think our due diligence
should allow for a little bit of time
here.
>> I'm not opposed to that. So I think we
can hold that off. Uh will you be ready
with it? Your thoughts on that next
week?
>> Oh, are you giving me homework now?
Well, you're the one that wants more
time, buddy.
>> Uh, yeah. Yeah, I'll I'll communicate
with you about that.
>> Excellent. Thank you.
>> And Chris, we just have about 10 minutes
left, so I would recommend uh the other
topics would probably take more than 10
minutes to cover. So, I would uh
recommend we do any final comments.
>> And I can't see the document. How are we
looking on it? I know there's a lengthy
definition portion I added to the end
that doesn't necessarily we could
probably delete that. I don't know how
much of it's actually going to be
relevant, but
>> no, we're actually doing very well. Uh
the next step is actually looking at the
required testing that will be necessary
and needed and uh so we'll be able to
cover a lot of that in the next week.
>> Okay. Um, one thing I would like people
to be aware of that I think might be a
conversation next time, I've gotten I've
had a couple conversations with Dan
and
um, most recently a lady named uh,
hold on a second. Let me look at my
notes. Rhonda Dantis from Silusions up
in Colorado.
And both of them are saying that the use
of total potential silosin
or total equivalent silus uh total
potential silosin is creating a lot of
confusion in their
markets and that maybe total equivalents
psilocybin would be a better um dosage
terminology to use. And I was in the
dosage committee meeting the other day
and I got I got
smacked down hard on that. But I I still
am not convinced based on the people
that I talked to that that's the right
way to go. So um and that's going to be
relevant in our next topic or next
conversation. So if if we think we
should go a different route to be
mindful of that.
Um hey uh okay
and what what else do we have? We have
our follow on meeting. Oh go ahead Greg.
Do you have a quick comment?
Yeah, I think as far as testing is
concerned, we can define the the um
the HLC or massspec definitions without
completing how it's communicated on
packaging. Um
the the measurements are going to be
things that no matter how they're
communicated will have to be tested for.
So I think we can breathe on the MTP PCN
psilocybin equivalency versus solosin
equivalency. I think we can breathe
Okay. Um,
got it. I also think that another one of
the lessons learned I've gotten was that
uh there's a lot of
there's not standards in throughout the
process. And so, um, I I would like to,
uh, potentially visit that and see where
everybody's landing on it, but I
understand what you're saying. So, um, I
think we'll shove that for now. Our next
meeting is scheduled for the 11th
and then we're going to submit our
recommendations to the board on the 13th
and then the board meeting is on the
27th. Um,
so my guess is we will not meet again
until probably the 4th. And I'm assuming
at that point the board will have
some ideas of, you know, no, we don't
like this. Go back, work on it. It's not
safe enough or or yes, this looks good.
Now work on that. Um,
so we'll see how that process goes. Um,
but I'll probably put in and we'll be
outside a legislative session at that
point, right, Dominic?
>> That is correct. Uh, the session ends um
next or I'm sorry, the uh 20th or 19th.
>> 19th.
>> I have now I have to look. I've been
looking at calendars all day. Let me
double check on that for everybody. The
19th.
>> The 19th. Excellent. So,
>> yeah,
>> I will probably request a and I'm just
going to glance at my calendar, a
in-person meeting and we'll do the first
one or a hybrid meeting uh in
Albuquerque for our first one and then
I'll I'll try to move them around. I
don't know how many of these we're going
to have, but I would like to see some of
you face to face for at least one of
these, which has been my intention all
along. Um,
but that would be when I expect our next
meeting.
Is there any other business or thoughts
people want to bring into the to the uh
the table before we close out? Chris,
just a little logistic item I just
wanted to bring up to everybody is as we
have been working with our IT um and as
they start to realize how many meetings
and documents that we have been doing,
they have actually allowed us a little
bit of an easier way to put the um the
meeting announcements. And so if you go
to our main mil medical psilocybin
program page on the left hand side and
I've got this up on the screen for those
who can see it, but on the left hand
side there's a psilocybin advisory board
link and if you go there what it does is
it brings you to that page and you'll
notice down below uh if you scroll down
just a little bit we are putting in all
the committee meeting dates and times
and updating this regularly with the
links to register. So, if for some
reason you're questioning or you have a
question about when the next set of
meetings are, you haven't been keeping
track of as far as the emails and all
that, you can go to this page and see
them. And as we're getting them
scheduled, we're putting them up and
then we are still uh every about every
week and a half, week, week and a half
sending out the updates as far as the
meetings themselves. But this way, it
makes it a little easier for people to
uh to be able to go and do this. Um, and
then just Shane, uh, Chris hasn't set a
date for that meeting. We'll talk about
the meeting for in person at the next
meeting, uh, which is going to be next
Wednesday, the 11th, February 11th. So,
great question there.
>> And thank you, Dez, for introducing
yourself in the chat.
>> And I'm I'm done other than to thank
everybody. Thank you all.
>> Yes. Thank you all.